<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article
          PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

<article id="rx">

<articleinfo>
   <title>The RX Document</title>
   <subtitle>X Consortium Standard</subtitle>
   <releaseinfo>Version 1.0</releaseinfo>
   <productnumber>X11 Release 6.4</productnumber>
   <authorgroup>
      <author>
         <firstname>Arnaud</firstname><surname>Le Hors</surname>
         <affiliation><orgname>X Consortium,
Inc.</orgname></affiliation>
         <email>lehors@x.org</email>
      </author>
   </authorgroup>

<abstract>
<para>
This document describes the RX MIME type and how it can be used to
provide
a means to execute remote applications, such as X Window System
clients,
from a World Wide Web browser. To achieve this, the RX document must
convey
enough information for an application to get everything it needs to
connect
to the various resources available in the user's environment and
display a
graphic user interface, possibly passing through some security firewall.
</para>
</abstract>

<legalnotice>
<para>
Copyright<trademark class='copyright'/>1996 X Consortium
</para>

<para>
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
"Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without
limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute,
sublicense, and sell copies of the Software, and to permit
persons to whom the Software
is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
</para>

<para>
The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included
in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.
</para>

<para>
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS
OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
THE X CONSORTIUM BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY,
WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT
OF OR
IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
SOFTWARE.
</para>

<para>
Except as contained in this notice, the name of the X Consortium shall
not be used in advertising or otherwise to promote the sale, use or other
dealings in this Software without prior written authorization from the
X Consortium.
</para>

</legalnotice>
</articleinfo>

<!-- <sect1 id = 'pgfId-105699'> -->
<sect1 id='introduction'>
<title>Introduction</title>

<para>
The RX MIME type <xref linkend='mime'/>
 document is designed to provide a means to execute
remote applications, such as X Window System clients, from a World Wide
Web browser. However, the document itself is not sufficient. To be of
any use. it requires the browser to use the information it contains and
to react accordingly. The general model is that the RX document conveys
to the browser the list of services the application needs to run. In
reaction the browser sets up the user environment for the application
to run, and starts the application by feeding the web server back the
relevant information. The RX document can list both required and
optional services, leaving the browser to decide, possibly based on user
preferences, which services are available and/or preferred.
</para>

<para>
This document describes the RX MIME type and how the browser is
expected to start the application by running a CGI script or equivalent <xref linkend='www_cgi'/>.
</para>
</sect1>

<!-- <sect1 id = 'pgfId-108267'> -->
<sect1 id = 'notational_conventions_and_generic_grammar'>
<title>Notational Conventions and Generic Grammar</title>

<para>
All of the mechanisms specified in this document are described in
both prose and an augmented Backus-Naur Form (BNF). Readers need to
be familiar with the notation in order to understand this
specification.
The augmented BNF includes the following constructs:
</para>

<variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>name = definition</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
The name of a rule is simply the name itself (without any enclosing
"&lt;" and "&gt;") and is separated from its definition by the equal
character "=". Whitespace is only significant in that indentation
of continuation lines is used to indicate a rule definition that
spans more than one line. Angle brackets are used within definitions
whenever their presence will facilitate discerning the use of rule
names.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>"literal"</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
Quotation marks surround literal text. Unless stated otherwise, the
text is case-insensitive.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>rule1 | rule2</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
Elements separated by a bar ("|") are alternatives, e.g.,
"yes | no" will accept yes or no.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>(rule1 rule2)</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
Elements enclosed in parentheses are treated as a single element. Thus,
"(elem (foo | bar) elem)" allows the token sequences "elem foo elem"
and "elem bar elem".
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>*rule</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
The character "*" preceding an element indicates repetition. The full
form is
"&lt;n&gt;*&lt;m&gt;element" indicating at least &lt;n&gt; and at most &lt;m&gt; occurrences of
element. Default values are 0 and infinity so that "*(element)" allows
any number, including zero; "1*element" requires at least one; and
"1*2element" allows one or two.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>[rule]</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
Square brackets enclose optional elements; "[foo bar]" is equivalent to
"*1(foo bar)".
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
</variablelist>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-107395'> -->
<sect2 id = 'basic_rules'>
<title>Basic Rules</title>

<para>
The following rules are used throughout this specification to describe
basic parsing constructs.
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='2' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>OCTET</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any 8-bit sequence of data&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>ALPHA</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any US-ASCII letter "A".."Z" and "a".."z"&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>DIGIT</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any US-ASCII digit "0".."9"&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>CHAR</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any character&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>CTL</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any US-ASCII control character
	 (octets 0 - 31) and DEL (127)&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>CR</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;US-ASCII CR, carriage return (13)&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>LF</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;US-ASCII LF, linefeed (10)&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>SP</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;US-ASCII SP, space (32)&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>HT</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;US-ASCII HT, horizontal-tab (9)&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>SPECIAL</entry>
      <entry>
= ";" | "?" | "," | "=" | "&lt;" | "&gt;" | SP | HT | CR | LF
      </entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>STRING</entry>
      <entry>= 1*&lt;any CHAR except CTLs and SPECIALs&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry>TEXT</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;any OCTET except CTLs, but including CR and LF&gt;</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- <sect1 id = 'pgfId-107148'> -->
<sect1 id = 'the_rx_mime_type'>
<title>The RX MIME type</title>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-107143'> -->
<sect2 id = 'general_form'>
<title>General form</title>

<para>
The general form of an RX document is a list of HTML PARAM elements, as
drafted by the WWW Consortium <xref linkend='insert_into_html'/> in its simplest form:
</para>

<screen>
"&lt;PARAM NAME=" name "VALUE=" value "&gt;"
</screen>

<para>
One advantage of this syntax is to provide HTML authors with the
possibility
to easily move elements from the RX document to the HTML document
itself,
when the OBJECT tag becomes standard and is fully supported by web
browsers.
The list of possible parameters is defined in the following section.
</para>

<para>
In addition the standard HTML comment element, which is of the form:
</para>

<screen>
"&lt;!--" TEXT "--&gt;"
</screen>

<para>
is supported.
</para>
</sect2>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-105729'> -->
<sect2 id = 'parameters'>
<title>Parameters</title>

<para>
First, an RX document can specify the RX version number with the
VERSION parameter which can have the following value (in augmented BNF):
</para>

<screen>
version	= 1*DIGIT "." 1*DIGIT
</screen>

<para>
This allows the document to specify a major and minor numbers. When not
specified the default value for this parameter is 1.0. When specified
this
must appear first in the document.
</para>

<para>
Then, an RX document can contain any of the parameters described below,
in any order:
</para>

<variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>ACTION</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
The URL to fetch to initiate the remote execution. It is equivalent to
the
DATA attribute of the OBJECT element and the SRC parameter of the
Netscape™ EMBED element.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>REQUIRED-SERVICES</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This indicates the list of services the application needs to run. This
list
can contain one or more of UI, PRINT as described below.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>UI</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This indicates the list of User Interface protocols the application
supports, in order of preference (from the most to the least preferred).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>PRINT</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This indicates the list of printing protocols the application support,
in order of preference (from the most to the least preferred).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>WIDTH and HEIGHT</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This allows the HTML author to specify the default geometry of
the application primary window.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>EMBEDDED</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This indicates whether the application is to be embedded in the
browser or not. If not specified in the RX document, the default
value is YES, unless overridden by browser or user settings.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>AUTO-START</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This specifies whether the application should be launched immediately
upon retrieval of the RX document or only on user demand. For instance,
this could be on a user click on the embedded region, or whatever other
user interface element the browser wants to provide for this. If not
specified in the RX document, the default value is YES, unless
overridden
by browser or user settings.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>APP-GROUP</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This specifies the logical application group to which the application
is
related. The intent of this attribute is to allow several remote
applications
to be considered as a single logical application or, on the contrary,
to
separate various applications from each other. If not specified in the
RX document,
the application is considered to be alone within its own logical group.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
</variablelist>

<para>
The possible values for each of these parameters is respectively
defined
as follows (in augmented BNF):
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">action</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;script URI&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">required-services</entry>
      <entry>= service *( "," service )</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>service</entry>
      <entry>	= "UI" | "PRINT"</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">ui</entry>
      <entry>= protocols</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>protocols</entry>
      <entry>= protocol *( "," protocol )</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>protocol</entry>
      <entry>= STRING</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">print</entry>
      <entry>= protocols</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">width</entry>
      <entry>= 1*DIGIT</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">height</entry>
      <entry>= 1*DIGIT</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">embedded</entry>
      <entry>= "YES" | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">auto-start</entry>
      <entry>= "YES" | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">app-group</entry>
      <entry>= STRING</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
In addition to this exhaustive list of parameters, an RX document can
also contain parameters only relevant to a particular protocol. The
names of these parameters must be prefixed by the related protocol name
and the value can be anything. There may be as many such parameters as
desired. These parameters are defined as follows:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">param-name</entry>
      <entry>= protocol "-" STRING</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">param-name</entry>
      <entry>= STRING</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
Every parameter can also be specified in the HTML document as an
attribute of the OBJECT or EMBED element when one is used. When this is
the case and a parameter is specified both in HTML and RX, the HTML
instance has precedence over the RX one. The only exception to this
rule is the VERSION parameter which only affects the set of parameters
to which it is attached, whether this is in HTML or RX.
</para>
</sect2>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-105849'> -->
<sect2 id = 'returned_parameters'>
<title>Returned Parameters</title>

<para>
Once the browser has read the RX document and performed any necessary
initialization, in response it should start the application at the
appropriate time (see auto-start) by fetching the action URI, via an
HTTP GET request <xref linkend='http_1_0'/>, with the following parameters list:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">return-parameters</entry>
      <entry>= *( "?" return-parameter )</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>return-parameter</entry>
      <entry>
= ui-return | print-return
| width-return | height-return | embedded-return
| extra-param-return
      </entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">ui-return</entry>
      <entry>= "UI=" ui-url</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">print-return</entry>
      <entry>= "PRINT=" print-url</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">width-return</entry>
      <entry>= "WIDTH=" 1*DIGIT</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">height-return</entry>
      <entry>= "HEIGHT=" 1*DIGIT</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">embedded-return</entry>
      <entry>= "EMBEDDED=" embedded</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">extra-param-return</entry>
      <entry>= protocol "-" STRING "=" STRING</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
For each requested service specified in the RX document the web browser
can respond with the corresponding return parameter. If any of the
requested services is not listed in the returned parameters, it should
be assumed that the service is unavailable.
</para>

<para>
The action URI, which should be a CGI script or equivalent, must not
only start the application with the given parameters, it is also
expected to produce a valid document of type "text/plain". The first
line of this document must contain an error code, either 0 for success
or non zero for failure. The non existence of this line should be
considered as a sign of failure. The rest of the document can then
contain some error messages to be displayed by the browser.
</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- <sect1 id = 'pgfId-105882'> -->
<sect1 id = 'how_the_rx_document_will_be_used_in_the_x_window_system'>
<title>How the RX document will be used in the X Window System</title>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-105884'> -->
<sect2 id = 'parameters_b'>
<title>Parameters</title>

<para>
In X for the UI and PRINT services respectively the protocols X and
XPRINT are supported and are then valid protocol names.
</para>

<para>
Also the following additional parameters are recognized:
</para>

<variablelist>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>X-UI-LBX, X-PRINT-LBX</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
These parameters indicate whether or not the application is LBX
capable. If not specified in the RX document, the default value is NO,
unless overridden by browser or user settings.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>X-UI-INPUT-METHOD</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This indicates that the application can make use of an input method
server. If not specified in the RX document, the default value is NO,
unless overridden by browser or user settings.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>X-AUTH</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
This parameter specifies a default list of authentication mechanisms,
in order of preference (from the most to the least preferred), applying
to all services.
      </para>
  </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>X-UI-AUTH, X-PRINT-AUTH, X-UI-LBX-AUTH, and X-PRINT-LBX-AUTH</term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
These parameters specify a list of authentication mechanisms, in order
of preference (from the most to the least preferred), applying to one
service in particular, that is X, XPRINT, LBX for X, and LBX for XPRINT
respectively. They have precedence over the global X-AUTH parameter
when both are specified.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
</variablelist>

<para>
The X-UI-LBX, X-PRINT-LBX parameters can have the following value:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">x-lbx</entry>
      <entry>= "YES" | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
The X-UI-INPUT-METHOD parameter can have the following value:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">x-ui-input-method</entry>
      <entry>= ( "YES" [ ";" URL ] ) | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
This specifies whether an input method server is available or not, and
if one is its location can be specified as an URL.
</para>

<para>
Each of the X-UI-AUTH, X-PRINT-AUTH, X-UI-LBX-AUTH, and
X-PRINT-LBX-AUTH parameters have the following value:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">xauths</entry>
      <entry>= xauth *( "," xauth)</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>xauth</entry>
      <entry>= xauth-name [ ":" xauth-data ]</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>xauth-name</entry>
      <entry>= 1*&lt;any CHAR except CTLs, SPECIALs and ":"&gt;</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>xauth-data</entry>
      <entry>= STRING</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
The authentication mechanism name can be for instance
MIT-MAGIC-COOKIE-1 or MIT-KERBEROS-5 while the authentication data
would be, respectively, nothing or a Kerberos principal and realm; for
instance "webserver@mycorp.com".
</para>
</sect2>

<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-109270'> -->
<sect2 id='returned_parameters_2'>
<title>Returned parameters</title>

<para>
In the GET request, the returned URLs for the UI and PRINT services,
that is for the X and XPRINT protocols, are of the form:
</para>


<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">ui-url</entry>
      <entry>= "x11:" xdisplay [ ";" auth ]</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>xdisplay</entry>
      <entry>= display | decnet-display</entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>display</entry>
      <entry>
= [ transport "/" ] host ":" display-num [ "." screen-num ]
      </entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>transport</entry>
      <entry>= "local" | "tcp" | "decnet"</entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>decnet-display
<footnote><para>
this syntax is supported for compatibility with Xlib and is equivalent
to the general display specification with decnet as the transport.
xauth is defined further.  One cannot specify an alternative such as,
an image, within the EMBED tag.
</para>
</footnote>
      </entry>
      <entry>= host "::" display-num [ "." screen-num ]</entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>host</entry>
      <entry>= &lt;A legal Internet host domain name or IP address (in
dotted-decimal form), as defined by Section 2.1 of RFC 1123&gt;
      </entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>display-num</entry>
      <entry>= 1*DIGIT</entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>screen-num</entry>
      <entry>= 1*DIGIT </entry>
    </row>

    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>auth</entry>
      <entry>= "auth=" xauth
<footnote><para>
this syntax is supported for compatibility with Xlib and is equivalent
to the general display specification with decnet as the transport.
xauth is defined further.  One cannot specify an alternative such as,
an image, within the EMBED tag.
</para>
</footnote>
      </entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">print-url</entry>
      <entry>= "xprint:" xprinter [ ";" auth]</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>xprinter</entry>
      <entry>
= [ printer-name "@" ][ transport "/" ] host ":" display-num
      </entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry></entry>
      <entry>printer-name</entry>
      <entry>= 1*&lt;any CHAR except CTLs, SPECIALs and "@"&gt;</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

<para>
And in response to the X-UI-LBX, X-PRINT-LBX parameters, the following
is given as part of the GET request:
</para>

<informaltable frame="none">
  <tgroup cols='3' align='left'>
  <colspec colname='c1' colsep="0" colwidth="1*"/>
  <colspec colname='c2' colsep="0" colwidth="3*"/>
  <colspec colname='c3' colsep="0" colwidth="10*"/>
  <tbody>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">x-ui-lbx-return</entry>
      <entry>= "X-UI-LBX=" ( "YES" [ ";" auth ] ) | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
    <row rowsep="0">
      <entry namest="c1" nameend="c2">x-print-lbx-return</entry>
      <entry>= "X-PRINT-LBX=" ( "YES" [ ";" auth ] ) | "NO"</entry>
    </row>
  </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</informaltable>

</sect2>
<!-- <sect2 id = 'pgfId-105923'> -->
<sect2 id = 'example'>
<title>Example</title>

<para>
An HTML document specifying an RX MIME-type document using the OBJECT
tag would look like:
</para>

<programlisting>
&lt;HTML&gt;
...
&lt;OBJECT data=http://www.domain.com/CalendarTool.rx
	type=application/x-rx
	width=500 height=400&gt;
&lt;IMG SRC=http://www.domain.com/CalendarTool.gif ALT=CalendarTool&gt;
&lt;/OBJECT&gt;
...
&lt;/HTML&gt;
</programlisting>

<para>
With the Netscape™ EMBED tag it would look like:
<footnote><para>
One cannot specify an alternative such as, an image, within the EMBED tag.
</para></footnote>
</para>

<programlisting>
&lt;HTML&gt;
...
&lt;EMBED SRC=http://www.domain.com/CalendarTool.rx width=500 height=400&gt;
...
&lt;/HTML&gt;
</programlisting>

<para>
The document SimCity.rx could contain the following:
</para>

<programlisting>
&lt;PARAM Name=VERSION Value=1.0&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=ACTION Value=http://www.domain.com/CalendarTool.pl&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=REQUIRED-SERVICES Value=UI&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=UI VALUE=X&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=X-UI-LBX Value=YES&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=X-AUTH Value=MIT-MAGIC-COOKIE-1&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=EMBEDDED Value=YES&gt;
&lt;PARAM Name=APP-GROUP Value=CalendarToolAppGroup1&gt;
</programlisting>

<para>
From which the browser would reply by a GET of the following URI:
</para>

<programlisting>
http://www.domain.com/CalendarTool.pl
	?UI=x11:myhost.mydomain.org:0;auth=MIT-MAGIC-COOKIE-1:044B3244D
	?WIDTH=500?HEIGHT=400?EMBEDDED=YES
	?X-UI-LBX=YES;auth=MIT-MAGIC-COOKIE-1:1A7C4C1F312B3
</programlisting>

<para>
Note that the URI is really made of a single line and is only presented
on several lines in this document to make it easier to read.
</para>
</sect2>

</sect1>

<bibliography id='references'>
<title>References</title>

<biblioentry id='uri_www'>
  <author>
    <firstname>T.</firstname><surname>Berners-Lee</surname>
  </author>
  <title>
Universal Resource Identifiers in WWW: A Unifying
Syntax for the Expression of Names and Addresses of Objects on the
Network as used in the World-Wide Web
  </title>
  <bibliomisc>
FC 1630, CERN, June 1994(http://ds.internic.net/rfc/rfc1630.txt)
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

<biblioentry id='url'>
  <authorgroup>
  <author>
    <firstname>T.</firstname><surname>Berners-Lee</surname>
  </author>
  <author>
    <firstname>L.</firstname><surname>Masinter</surname>
  </author>
  <author>
    <firstname>M.</firstname><surname>McCahill</surname>
  </author>
  </authorgroup>
  <title>Uniform Resource Locators (URL)</title>
  <bibliomisc>
RFC 1738, CERN, Xerox Corporation, University of
Minnesota, December 1994
(http://ds.internic.net/rfc/rfc1738.txt).
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

<biblioentry id='http_1_0'>
  <authorgroup>
    <author>
      <firstname>T.</firstname><surname>Berners-Lee</surname>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>R.</firstname><surname>Fielding</surname>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>H.</firstname><surname>Frystyk</surname>
    </author>
  </authorgroup>
  <title>Hypertext Transfer Protocol -- HTTP/1.0</title>
  <bibliomisc>
May 1996, (http://www.ics.uci.edu/pub/ietf/http/rfc1945.html)
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

<biblioentry id='mime'>
  <authorgroup>
    <author>
      <firstname>N.</firstname><surname>Borenstein</surname>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>N.</firstname><surname>Freed</surname>
    </author>
  </authorgroup>
  <title>
MIME (Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions) Part One:
Mechanisms for Specifying and Describing the
Format of Internet Message Bodies
  </title>
  <bibliomisc>
RFC 1521, Bellcore, Innosoft,
September 1993 (http://ds.internic.net/rfc/rfc1521.txt).
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

<biblioentry id='insert_into_html'>
  <author>
    <firstname>Dave</firstname><surname>Raggett</surname>
  </author>
  <title>
Inserting objects into HTML
  </title>
  <bibliomisc>
W3C Working Draft 22-Apr-96
(http://www.w3.org/pub/WWW/TR/WD-object-960422.html)
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

<biblioentry id='www_cgi'>
  <author>
    <firstname>David</firstname><surname>Robinson</surname>
  </author>
  <title>
The WWW Common Gateway Interface Version 1.1
  </title>
  <bibliomisc>
University of Cambridge UK, 15 February 1996
(http://www.ast.cam.ac.uk/~drtr/cgi-spec.html)
  </bibliomisc>
</biblioentry>

</bibliography>

</article>
